Register to The Henry Gilbert Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Music, 1891-1927; Series I; 11.9' (20 boxes)
  - Choral, I.G
    - [To Thee! America] To Thee! America: Hymn; for mixed chorus and orchestra (Box 14, Folder 278)
      - [To Thee! America] To Thee! America: Hymn; for mixed chorus and orchestra, 1 score (28 p.), bound; 36 cm.
        [1914].
      - [To Thee! America] To Thee! America: Hymn; for mixed chorus and orchestra, Two photographs (negatives) of pp. 8-9 of the above holograph score; 20 x 25 cm.
        Made of flammable material - discarded.
    - [To Thee! America (Sketch)], 1 score ([24] p.); 33 cm. (Box 14, Folder 280)
    - [To Thee! America. Vocal score] To America: hymn; for mixed chorus. - S.l.: [C.C. Birchard], c1914. (Box 14, Folder 281)
      - [To Thee! America. Vocal score] To America: hymn; for mixed chorus. - S.l.: [C.C. Birchard], c1914., 1 vocal score (12 p.); 27 cm.
        Three copies with markings.
      - [To Thee! America. Vocal score] To America: hymn; for mixed chorus. - S.l.: [C.C. Birchard], c1914., 1 vocal score (13 p.); 36 cm.
        Acc. arr. for piano.
        "Copyright, 1914, C.C. Birchard & Company" - p. 1.
    - ['Twas brillig and the slithy toves...(Sketch)], 1 score (4 p.); 34 cm. (Box 14, Folder 282)
      For chorus and orchestra.
    - Miscellaneous unidentified sketches, Loose sheets ([8] p.); 35 cm. (Box 14, Folder 283)
  - Keyboard, I.H
    - [Albumleaf], [2] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 15, Folder 284)
    - [Allegretto fugato], 4 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 15, Folder 285)
    - [American dances; arr.] Three American dances: for piano four-hands. - Boston: Boston Music Co., c1919., 23 p. of music; 30 cm. (Box 15, Folder 286)
      See also: A. Opera and Incidental. Uncle Remus; and B. Orchestra. American dances.
    - [Comedy overture on negro themes; arr.] Comedy overture on negro themes: 4 hand arr., 25 p. of music, bound; 34 cm. (Box 15, Folder 287)
      See also: A. Opera and Incidental. Uncle Remus; and B. Orchestra. Comedy overture on negro themes.
    - [Coolin], [1] sheet of music; 34 cm. (Box 15, Folder 288)
    - [Crassafox], 7 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 15, Folder 289)
    - [Dance in Place Congo; arr.], 28 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 15, Folder 290)
      Portion of folder labeled by Henry Gilbert laid in: "Piano score The Dance in Place Congo Symphonic Ballet..."
    - [Dance in Place Congo. Selections; arr.] Dance after meas. 396., 4 p. of music; 33 cm. (Box 15, Folder 291)
      See: B. Orchestra. Dance in Place Congo.
    - [David Swan] David Swan: after Hawthorne, [4] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 15, Folder 292)
    - [Dewey Schottische], 2 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 15, Folder 292)
    - [Dewey Schottische] Schottische, [1] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 15, Folder 292)
      Different version than the above.
    - [Dewey Schottische (Sketch)] Schottische strains, [2] p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 15, Folder 292)
      See also: B. Orchestra. Dewey Schottische.
    - [Episodes. Negro episode; arr.] Newton Center, Mass.: Wa-Wan Press, c1907., 5 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 15, Folder 293)
      Two copies, one with note from Mrs. Henry Gilbert.
      See also: B. Orchestra. Episodes.
    - [Fantasie], [4] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 15, Folder 294)
    - [Fugato, C major], [2] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 15, Folder 294)
    - [Fugato], [2] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 15, Folder 294)
      Incomplete, lacking last pages.
    - [Fughette], [2] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 15, Folder 295)
      Dated: 1891 Jun 16.
    - [Fugue], [2] p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 15, Folder 296)
    - Humoreski
      See: A. Opera and Incidental. Uncle Remus (Sketches).
    - [Indian sketches; arr.] Indian sketches: 4 hand arrangement, 53 p. of music, bound; 34 cm. (Box 15, Folder 297)
      See also: B. Orchestra. Indian scenes.
    - [Intermezzo], [3] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 15, Folder 298)
      "1890s" - folder.
    - [Intimate story of Indian tribal life. Indian scenes; arr.] Indian scenes: five pieces: for the pianoforte. - New York: H.W. Gray, c1912., 23 p. of music: ill.; 31 cm. (Box 15, Folder 299)
      Contents: 1. By the arrow - 2. The night scout - 3. In the Kutenai country - 4. Signal fire to the mountain god - 5. On the Jocko.
      See also: A. Opera and Incidental. Intimate story
    - [Island of the Fay; arr.] Newton Center, Mass.: Wa-Wan Press, 1904 (Vol. II [summer quarter] Part II: July)., 12 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 15, Folder 300)
      Two copies, one with pencil marking by Henry Gilbert?
      See also: B. Orchestra. Island of the Fay.
    - [March], [5] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 15, Folder 301)
      Dated: 1901 Aug 29.
      "March in C for piano" - cover.
    - [Mazurka (c1902)] Newton Center, Mass.: Wa-Wan Press, c1902., 5 p. (1 copy 3 p.) of music; 35 cm. (Box 15, Folder 302)
      Three copies, one published with Gilbert's "Scherzo" and Harvey Worthington Loomis's "Star rays."
    - [Mazurka (no date)], [2] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 15, Folder 303)
    - [Minuet, B-flat major], [1] p. of music; 30 cm. (Box 15, Folder 304)
      With: "Sarabande."
    - [Minuet, C major], [1] sheet of music; 15 x 27 cm. (Box 15, Folder 304)
    - [Minuet], [2] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 15, Folder 304)
    - [Mittenacht?], [2] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 15, Folder 304)
      Words to poem by Heine at top of page.
    - [Negro dances]
      See: Uncle Remus. Negro dances; arr.
    - [Orlamonde; arr.], 23 p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 15, Folder 305)
      Words in French by M. Maeterlinck on p. 1.
      Pencil and ink sketch (1 sheet) at end.
    - [Orlamonde; arr. (Sketches)], Loose sheets [7] p. of music; 27 x 34 cm. (Box 15, Folder 305)
    - [Pavane (Sketch)], [2] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 15, Folder 306)
    - [Prelude (1898)], [2] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 15, Folder 307)
      Dated: 1898 Apr 14.
    - [Prelude (1890's)], [3] p. of music; 31 cm. (Box 15, Folder 307)
    - [Prelude (Sketch)], [2] p. of music; 27 x 34 cm. (Box 15, Folder 307)
    - [Prelude (no date)], [2] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 15, Folder 307)
    - [Rag a bag] Rag a bag: 6 early American pieces; for piano... / edited and fingered by Alfred DeVoto. (Box 15, Folder 308)
      - [Rag a bag] Rag a bag: 6 early American pieces; for piano... / edited and fingered by Alfred DeVoto., [12] p. of music; 35 cm.
        Op. 19.
        "...A final copy probably used by printer" - folder.
      - [Rag a bag] Rag a bag: 6 early American pieces; for piano... / edited and fingered by Alfred DeVoto., Photostat (negative) of above holograph, score; 27 x 36 cm.
        Does not contain markings.
      - [Rag a bag] Rag a bag: 6 early American pieces; for piano... / edited and fingered by Alfred DeVoto., 18 p. of music; 31 cm.
        Edited and fingered by Alfred DeVoto.
        Two copies, one inscribed to Morton Gould by Helen K. Gilbert, 1943 May 9.
    - [Riders to the sea; arr.] Riders to the sea: 4 hand arr., 17 p. of music; 33 cm. (Box 15, Folder 309)
      Portion of cover with note by Henry Gilbert laid in.
    - [Roycroft march], [3] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 15, Folder 310)
      "Dedicated to Fra Elbertus and the rest of the faithful" - p. [1].
    - [Sarabanda], [1] p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 15, Folder 311)
      Unidentified sketch on back.
    - [Sarabande, A-flat major], [1] sheet of music; 35 cm. (Box 15, Folder 311)
    - [Sarabande, C minor], [1] p. of music; 30 cm. (Box 15, Folder 304)
      With: Minuet, B-flat major.
    - [Sarabande, G minor], [1] sheet of music; 35 cm. (Box 15, Folder 311)
    - [Sarabande (Sketch)], Loose sheet [2] p. of music; 25 x 32 cm. (Box 15, Folder 311)
    - [Scherzo] Newton Center, Mass.: Wa-Wan Press, 1902., pp. 4-8 of music; 35 cm. (Box 15, Folder 302)
      With: Gilbert's "Mazurka" and Harvey Worthington Loomis's "Star rays."
    - [Scrap No. 2], [1] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 15, Folder 312)
      "No. 8" - p. [1].
      Note on back.
    - [Soldiers three march] Composed for Armistice Day, 1926 / by Henry F. Gilbert; Stuart Mason, and Edward Ballantine., 1 sheet of music; 28 x 43 cm. (Box 15, Folder 313)
      Photocopy.
      In: Boston Sunday Post, 1926 Nov 7, Section D-7.
      Copyright, 1926, the Post Publishing Co.
    - [Sonatas, piano, F major] Sonata, [3] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 15, Folder 313)
      "Piano sonata - fragment - ca. 1891-92 (?)" - folder.
    - [Sonatas, piano (Sketch)], [6] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 15, Folder 313)
    - [Story (Sketch)], [1] sheet of music; 36 cm. (Box 15, Folder 314)
      "Story - 1890s" - folder.
    - [Suite, piano (Sketch)?], Loose sheets ([21] p.); 6-24 cm. (Box 15, Folder 315)
      "Fragments of piano suite (?) Later manuscript - handwriting - Presto, vivace, complete" - folder.
    - Tempo di rag
      See: D. Chamber and Instrumental. Tempo di rag.
    - [Uncle Remus. Negro dances; arr.] Negro dances. - New York: H.W. Gray, c1914., 24 p. of music; 31 cm. (Box 15, Folder 316)
      "Five pieces for the pianoforte" - cover.
    - [Uncle Remus. Negro dances. V; arr.] (Box 15, Folder 317)
      - [Uncle Remus. Negro dances. V; arr.], 4 p. of music; 33 cm.
        "Copyright H.W. Gray" - p. [1].
      - [Uncle Remus. Negro dances. V; arr.], pp. 21-23 [sheets] of music; 35 cm.
        Proof sheets from published score with markings.
        "H.L.B." in lower right-hand corner of each sheet.
    - [Verlaine moods] Two Verlaine moods (Box 15, Folder 318)
      - [Verlaine moods] Two Verlaine moods, [3], [5], 7 p. of music; 34cm.
        Holographs (No. I signed) in ink with pencil markings.
        Three numbers?
        "Op. 8 - 1903" - Grove...
        Contents: I. Donc, ce sera par un clair jour d'été - II and III untitled.
      - [Verlaine moods] Two Verlaine moods, pp. 4-11 of music; 35 cm.
        Contains pencil markings.
        Published with: Gilman's "A dream of death."
        Pencil sketch (27 cm.) laid in.
      - [Verlaine moods] Two Verlaine moods, 9 p. of music; 35 cm.
        Contains many corrections by Henry Gilbert.
        Two proof copies with pencil and ink sketches (C4] p.) laid in.
    - Unidentified pieces, [2], [2] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 15, Folder 319)
      Pencil sketch ([2] p.) laid in.
    - Unidentified piece (Sketch), [2] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 15, Folder 319)
      "Untitled piano piece - 1890s" - folder.
  - Miscellaneous, I.I
    - School song books
      - [Elementary music] Boston, etc.: Ginn and company, c1923., 192 p. of music; 21 cm. (Box 16)
        Contains works by Henry Gilbert: Bunny, Coasting, Pigtail, Signs of spring.
        Contains annotations by Henry Gilbert.
      - [Introductory music] Boston, etc.: Ginn and company, c1923., 176 p. of music; 21 cm. (Box 16)
        Contains song by Henry Gilbert: Goodnight.
      - [New second music reader] Boston, etc.: Ginn & company, c1904., 122 p. of music; 20 cm. (Box 16)
        Contains works by Henry Gilbert: Clinkum Clankum, Ill wind that blew somebody good, and Merry-go-round.
      - [Second music reader] Boston, etc.: Ginn & company, c1906., 128 p. of music; 21 cm. (Box 16)
        Contains works by Henry Gilbert: Clinkum Clankum, Grasshopper green, Ill wind that blew somebody good, and Merry-go-round.
    - Sketchbooks
      - [Americana] Americana: (not negro), [31] p. of music; 13 x 20 cm. (Box 17, Folder 320)
        Holograph in pencil and ink with notes inside covers.
        Title from cover.
      - [Folk songs], 77 [i.e., 12 p.] of music; 26 cm. (Box 17, Folder 320)
        Loose sheet with notes laid in back.
        Contents: "Slavic - Magyar - Romany - Sailor chanties etc. - Spanish."
      - [Folk songs (Untitled)] (Box 17, Folder 321)
        - [Folk songs (Untitled)], [32] p. of music; 19 x 24 cm.
          "England. Wales. Scotland. Ireland. Norway. Sweden. Denmark" - cover.
        - [Folk songs (Untitled)], [26] p. of music; 19 x 24 cm.
      - [Indian], 43, [13] p. of music; 13 x 17 cm. (Box 17, Folder 322)
        Holograph in pencil with notes on inside of cover.
      - [Melodies (Book No. 1)], 60 [i.e., 13] p.; 13 x 17 cm. (Box 17, Folder 323)
        "Sample melodies by various composers in different times" - note inside front cover.
      - [Melodies (Book No. 2)] Melodies: (from great composers), 31 [i.e., 15], [10] p. of music; 12 x 17 cm. (Box 17, Folder 323)
        Notes inside back cover, and on 2 sheets which are laid in.
      - [Melodies (original)], 36 [i.e., 14] p. of music; 11 x 20 cm. (Box 17, Folder 324)
        Note inside front cover.
      - [Negro folklore], [47], [6] p. of music; 11 x 15 cm. (Box 17, Folder 324)
        Notes on inside of both covers.
      - [Rag-time sketches] Rag-time sketches: possible rhythms, 60 p. of music; 11 x 15 cm. (Box 17, Folder 325)
      - [Slavic], [21] p. of music; 19 x 24 cm. (Box 17, Folder 326)
        "Russia - Bohemia - Moravia - Poland - South Slavic - Misc. slavic" - cover.
      - [Student exercises]
        - [Student exercises], [24] p. of music; 20 x 24 cm. (Box 17, Folder 327)
          "Henry F. Gilbert. Somerville. Mass." - cover.
        - [Student exercises], [96] p. of music; 26 x 32 cm. (Box 17, Folder 328)
          Holograph in pencil with ink markings.
          Larfer sheet laid in.
          Cover removed for conservation.
        - George Howard, instructor, 4 sketchbooks of music; 20-24 cm. (Box 17, Folder 329)
        - George Whiting, instructor, [6] p. of music; 24 cm. (Box 17, Folder 329)
        - "Harmony", iii p. of music; 19 x 24 cm. (Box 17, Folder 329)
      - Miscellaneous untitled sketchbooks (Box 17, Folder 330-333)
        - Miscellaneous untitled sketchbooks, [54] p. of music; 11 x 15 cm.
          Clipping re Irish music (photocopy) laid in.
        - Miscellaneous untitled sketchbooks, [48] p. of music; 11 x 15 cm.
          First page headed "Vocal."
          Notes inside back cover.
        - Miscellaneous untitled sketchbooks, 26, [24] p. of music; 15 cm.
          "Melodic nubs. pg. 26 - From Ainsworthy. pg. 20 - Old N.E. Hymn. 16 - Sailor songs. pg. 19" - cover.
          Note inside back cover.
        - Miscellaneous untitled sketchbooks, 45, [5], 10 p. of music; 12 x 15 cm.
          "Various motives etc., page 1 - Rococo, page 15 - Symphonic, page 30 - Dance, end of book page 40" - inside front cover.
        - Miscellaneous untitled sketchbooks, [47] p. of music; 11 x 15 cm.
          Front page headed "March."
        - Miscellaneous untitled sketchbooks, [60] p. of music, bound; 15 cm.
          First page headed "From J.C. Mangan P. and P. of Munster: The maiden (p. 88)."
          Notes on insides of covers.
        - Miscellaneous untitled sketchbooks, [54] p. of music, bound; 11 x 15 cm.
          First page headed "Dance Rhythms."
          Notes on inside of covers, 3 sheets of notes laid in, and 2 sheets of notes attached to cover.
        - Miscellaneous untitled sketchbooks, [52] p. of music, bound; 13 x 17 cm.
          First page headed "From Karpenko - Cole - Reiss songs."
          Notes inside both covers.
          Sheet headed "Simultaneous combination of rhythms on sheets no. 1 and no. 2" laid in.
        - Miscellaneous untitled sketchbooks, 26 [i.e., 11], [35] p. of music; 13 x 16 cm.
          First page headed "American tunes," first page of same sketchbook (upside down and reverse) headed "Sketches."
    - Transcriptions and arrangements of North American Indian music and folk songs
      - Transcriptions of North American Indian music from cylinder recordings collected by Edward S. Curtis and published in his work The North American Indian
        See also: III.H. CORRESPONDENCE. Re Gilbert's collaboration with Edward S. Curtis.
        - Transcriptions of North American Indian music from cylinder recordings collected by Edward S. Curtis and published in his work The North American Indian, Loose sheets ([126] p.); 24-35 cm. (Box 18, Folder 334)
          Numbered "Record 401-576", missing many numbers.
          Duration of scenes recorded in right hand corner of each sketch.
        - Transcriptions of North American Indian music from cylinder recordings collected by Edward S. Curtis and published in his work The North American Indian, Loose sheets ([65] p.); 27-36 cm. (Box 18, Folder 335)
    - Miscellaneous folk songs from China, England, France, Germany, Ireland, Japan, Netherlands, Poland, Russia, Sweden, and Wales, as well as sea songs and slave songs., Loose sheets ([39] p.); 9-35 cm. (Box 18, Folder 336)
      Mostly holographs in pencil and ink.
    - Studies and exercises, Loose sheets (ca. 147 p.); 16-36 cm. (Box 18, Folder 337)
      "Winter 1923?" - sheet laid in folder.
    - Miscellaneous unidentified sketches, Loose sheets (c. 830 p.); various sizes. (Box 18; 19; 92, Folder 338-348; 340-355; 356)
      Sketches which were found together in envelopes or folders remain together.
- Music by Others, 1843-1917; Series II; 3.75' (9 boxes)
  This series is divided into the following subseries:
  A. Arranged by Gilbert (Arranged alphabetically by composer)
  B. By Benjamin Franklin Gilbert [father]: 1. Holograph and manuscript music probably all by or arranged by Benjamin F. Gilbert, and 2. Published vocal music
  C. By James L. Gilbert [uncle] (Arranged alphabetically by title
  D. Miscellaneous Works
  - Music by Others Arranged by Gilbert, II.A
    Arranged alphabetically by composer.
    - Bourée from 2nd violin sonata, Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750; 10 parts; 10-34 cm. (Box 19, Folder 1)
      For flute, oboe, clarinet, cornet, violin I-II, violoncello, bass, and piano.
    - Prelude I, Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750; [1] sheet; 34 cm. (Box 19, Folder 2)
      "Sarabande" crossed out on back.
    - Sonata for viola da gamba and clavier no. 2 transcribed for violin, Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750; 1 part (3 p.); 35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 2)
      Violin part.
    - Hungarian march, Berlioz, Hector, 1803-1869; 1 part ([1] p.); 34 cm. (Box 19, Folder 3)
      Unidentified part.
    - L'Arlésienne Suite No. 4 Carillon, Bizet, Georges, 1838-1875; 15 parts; 15-35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 4)
      For flute I-II, oboe, clarinet I-II, horn, trombone, violin I-II, viola, violoncello, bass, and piano.
    - Symphonie no. 2, Borodin, Aleksandr Porfirʹevich, 1833-1887; 2 parts; 18-35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 5)
      Portions of cornet and piano parts only.
    - Der Gang zum Liebchen... op. 49 no. 1, Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897; 1 part; 35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 6)
      "Violin obligato [sic] (H.F.G.)."
    - Herbstgefühl... op. 48-9, Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897; 1 part; 27 cm. (Box 19, Folder 6)
      "Violin obligato (H.F.G.)"
    - Trio: for pianoforte violin horn, Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897; 1 part (6 p.); 34 cm. (Box 19, Folder 6)
      Manuscript in ink. "Cornet in Bb (with Hat)."
    - Piper's galliard, Bull, John; [1] sheet of music; 33 cm. (Box 19, Folder 7)
      "I long for the wedding" - on back.
    - Intermezzo, Chadwick, G. W. (George Whitefield), 1854-1931; 4 parts; 35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 8)
      Parts for flute, clarinet, cornet, and oboe only.
    - Mazurka no. 19 / [by] Chopin; arr. Henry F. Gilbert, Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849 (Box 19, Folder 9)
      - Mazurka no. 19 / [by] Chopin; arr. Henry F. Gilbert, 1 score (8 p.); 34 cm.
      - Mazurka no. 19 / [by] Chopin; arr. Henry F. Gilbert, 7 parts; 35 cm.
        Flute, oboe, clarinet, cornets, violin, violoncello, and piano parts only.
    - Op. 28 - No. 7, Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849; 1 score ([1] p.); 35 cm.
      Manuscript in pencil.
      Arr. for flutes, oboe, clarinets, bassoons, horns, violin, viola, violoncello, and bass.
    - [Prelude, piano, E minor (Sketch)], Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849; 1 score ([1] p.); 27 x 35 cm.
    - Sousedské, 4 parts; 35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 10)
      Violin I-II, viola, and violoncello parts.
      Creator unknown, possibly Chwala (firstname unknown).
    - Air de danse de Lakmé, Delibes, Léo, 1836-1891; 2 parts; 35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Ballet music from Sylvia, Delibes, Léo, 1836-1891; 5 parts; 27 cm. (Box 19, Folder 11)
      Manuscript in pencil and ink.
      Violin I-II, viola, and violoncello parts only.
    - Sylvia (Ballet): Pas des Ethiopiens, Delibes, Léo, 1836-1891; 13 parts; 35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 11)
      For violin I-II, viola, violoncello, bass, flute, oboe, clarinets, cornets, trombone, and piano.
      Unidentified and incomplete clarinet part laid inside.
    - Sylvia (Ballet): Prelude - Les chasseresses, Delibes, Léo, 1836-1891; 12 parts; 35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 11)
      For violin I-III, viola, and violoncello parts only.
    - Allemande G... clavecin et 3 violes, Du Mont, Henry; 4 p. of music; 33 cm. (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Scherzo from Terzette, Dvořák, Antonín, 1841-1904; 4 parts; 34 cm. (Box 19, Folder 13)
      Violin 1 (2), violin II, and viola parts only.
    - Suite op. 39: II Polka, Dvořák, Antonín, 1841-1904; 1 part; 35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 13)
      Violin I part.
    - Waltz, Dvořák, Antonín, 1841-1904; 8 parts; 34 cm. (Box 19, Folder 13)
      For piano, flute, clarinet, horn, cornets, violin I-II, and violoncello.
      Op. 54, Dvorák's arrangement of Waltz for string orchestra.
    - Unidentified piece (Sketch), Dvořák, Antonín, 1841-1904; [2] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Psyché: symphonic poem; 1st movement, Le sommeil de Psyché, Franck, César, 1822-1890; 7 parts; 35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 14)
      For piano, flute, clarinet, cornet, violin I-II, and violoncello.
    - La cinquantaine, Gabriel-Marie (Box 19, Folder 15)
      - La cinquantaine, pp. 120-123 of music; 33 cm.
        Published for piano and arranged by Henry Gilbert for piano, cornet, and violin; violin part (manuscript) included.
        Published with: Hauser's "Cradle song" and Lack's "Valse time."
      - La cinquantaine, 2 parts; 34 cm.
        Cornet and violin parts.
    - Fantasie no. 6, Gibbons, Orlando, 1583-1625; 2 parts; 35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 16)
      Violin I-II parts.
      With: Purcell's "Sonata II."
    - Symphony (1st movement), Goetz, Hermann Gustave; 11 parts; 34 cm. (Box 19, Folder 17)
      For piano, flute, clarinet, cornets, horn, trombone, violin I-II, viola, and violoncello.
      In F major.
    - Anitra's dance from Peer Gynt Suite, Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907; 8 parts; 35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 18)
      For piano, flute, oboe, clarinet, cornet, violin I-II, and violoncello.
    - Aus Holberg's Zeit: Air: IV, Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907; 3 parts; 35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 18)
      Violin I-II and viola parts only.
    - Der Frühling, Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907; 7 parts; 34 cm. (Box 19, Folder 18)
      Violin I-II, viola I-II, violoncello, and bass parts.
      With: "Herzwunden."
    - Herzwunden, Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907; 7 parts; 34 cm. (Box 19, Folder 18)
      With: "Der Frühling."
    - Norwegian dance no. 2, Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907; 9 parts; 17-35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 18)
      For piano, flute, oboe, clarinet, cornet, violin I-II, violoncello, and bass.
    - Suite from the music to Peer Gynt, Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907; 3 parts; 35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 18)
      Piano, clarinet, and cornet parts only.
    - Vöglein, Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907; 1 score ([4] p.); 27 x 34 cm. (Box 19, Folder 18)
      Arr. for flutes, oboes, clarinets, bassoons, horns, violins, violas, violoncellos, and basses.
    - Lelawala: Indian legend, Hadley, Henry Kimball; 1 part; 34 cm. (Box 19, Folder 19)
      Oboe II and English horn parts.
    - Rhapsodie no. 1 ... op. 17, Hallen, Andréas; 13 parts; 35 cm. (Box 20, Folder 20)
      Manuscript in ink, string parts published.
      For piano, flutes, oboe, clarinets, horn, cornets, trombone, violin I-II, viola, violoncello, and bass.
      String parts published in Leipzig: Fr. Kistner.
    - Phrases from Handel, Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759; [2] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 20, Folder 21)